export default {
  notes: [
    {
      heading: "Introduction",
      content: "Electric charge is a fundamental property of matter..."
    }
  ],
  mcqs: [
    {
      question: "SI unit of charge is?",
      options: ["Coulomb", "Ampere", "Volt", "Ohm"],
      answer: 0
    }
  ],
  pyqs: [
   

{
  question: "The order and degree of (d²y/dx²)² + (dy/dx)² = x sin(dy/dx) are:",
  options: [
    "(A) order 2, degree 2",
    "(B) order 1, degree not defined",
    "(C) order 2, degree not defined",
    "(D) order 2, degree 1"
  ],
  answer: "(C) order 2, degree not defined"
},

{
  question: "The order and degree of −d⁴y/dx⁴ + 2e^(dy/dx) + y² = 0 are:",
  options: [
    "(A) 4 , not defined",
    "(B) −4,1",
    "(C) 4,1",
    "(D) 1,1"
  ],
  answer: "(A) 4 , not defined"
},

{
  question: "The solution of log(dy/dx)=3x+4y is:",
  options: [
    "(A) 3e^(4y)+4e^(−3x)+C=0",
    "(B) 3e^(−4y)+4e^(3x)+12C=0",
    "(C) e^(3x+4y)+C=0",
    "(D) 3e^(−3y)+4e^(4x)+12C=0"
  ],
  answer: "(C) e^(3x+4y)+C=0"
},

{
  question: "If p and q are order and degree of d/dx[(dy/dx)³]=0, then (p−q) equals:",
  options: ["(A) 0","(B) 3","(C) 2","(D) 1"],
  answer: "(A) 0"
},

{
  question: "The degree of (y'')² + (y')³ = x sin(y') is:",
  options: ["(A) 3","(B) 2","(C) 1","(D) undefined"],
  answer: "(D) undefined"
},

{
  question: "General solution of x dy + y dx = 0 is:",
  options: [
    "(A) logy=logx+C",
    "(B) x+y=C",
    "(C) x²+y²=C²",
    "(D) xy=C"
  ],
  answer: "(D) xy=C"
},

{
  question: "Order of d⁴y/dx⁴ − sin(d²y/dx²)=5 is:",
  options: ["(A) not defined","(B) 2","(C) 3","(D) 4"],
  answer: "(D) 4"
},

{
  question: "Solution of x dx + y dy = 0 is:",
  options: [
    "(A) x + y = C",
    "(B) xy = C",
    "(C) logx − logy = C",
    "(D) 1/x + 1/y = C"
  ],
  answer: "(B) xy = C"
},

{
  question: "Degree of sinx + cos(dy/dx) = y² is:",
  options: ["(A) not defined","(B) 1","(C) 0","(D) 2"],
  answer: "(A) not defined"
},

{
  question: "Number of arbitrary constants in particular solution of a second order differential equation is:",
  options: ["(A) 3","(B) 1","(C) 2","(D) 0"],
  answer: "(C) 2"
},

{
  question: "Degree of 1 + (dy/dx)² = x is:",
  answer: "2"
},

{
  question: "Order and degree of x² d²y/dx² = {1+(dy/dx)²}⁴ are:",
  answer: "Order = 2, Degree = 4"
},

{
  question: "Order and degree of (d⁴y/dx⁴)² = [x + (dy/dx)²]³ are:",
  answer: "Order = 4, Degree = 2"
},

{
  question: "Order and degree of d²y/dx² + x(dy/dx)² = 2x² log(d²y/dx²) are:",
  answer: "Order = 2, Degree = not defined"
}



  ]
};
